Guide to the Papers of Abby Weed Grey 1922-1978 MC.151
New York University Archives
Abby Weed Grey Papers
1922-1978
New York University Archives
MC.151
29.75 Linear Feet in 32 manuscript boxes, 6 flat boxes, and 5 record cartons.
The Abby Weed Grey Papers span the years 1922-1978, with the bulk of the material covering the period 1960-1974. The papers document Mrs. Grey's world travels, published and unpublished works, and her collection and curation of art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in series and subseries determined before the collection arrived at the University Archives.
The series and subseries arrangement of the collection is as follows:
Book Copy
Unpublished Works
AWG Notebooks, 1945-1978
Travel Diaries, 1960-1973
Artist Files
Index Cards, 1947-1978
Misc. Activities and Memorabilia, 1959-1975
Correspondence
Tanavoli, Parviz
Grey Gallery and Study Center NYU
The University of Minnesota
The Grey Foundation
Scrapbooks
The Grey Foundation Exhibitions 1961-1972
Oversized materials
Multimedia
Abby Weed Grey Photographs
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Portrait and Biographical Files in the New York University Archives
New York University Photograph Collection, NYU Buildings, Grey Gallery and Study Center
"Abby Weed Grey," page from the Grey Art Gallery web site: http://www.nyu.edu/greyart/information/Abby_Weed_Grey/body_abby_weed_grey.html
The following reference materials:
Grey, Abby Weed. The Picture is the Window, The Window is the Picture: An Autobiographical Journey. New York: New York University Press, 1983.
One World Through Art: A Selection of 1001 Works of Art from the Ben and Abby Grey Foundation. St. Paul, Minn.: Ben and Abby Grey Foundation, 1972.
Scope and Contents
The Abby Weed Grey Papers span the years 1922-1978, with the bulk of the material covering the period 1960-1974. These papers illustrate Mrs. Grey's world travels and her interest in art. Documentation is most extensive pertaining to the writing of her autobiography entitled "The Picture is the Window, The Window is the Picture: An Autobiographical Journey". They also provide information on the Iranian artist-sculptor Parviz Tanavoli and Mrs. Grey's gift to New York University to fund the Grey Art Gallery and Study Center. The collection also contains some material related to her earlier life.
Materials in Series I - XV include published and unpublished materials of Abby Weed Grey's writing; information on international artists; correspondence between Grey and artists, in particular Parviz Tanavoli; catalogs, publicity and clippings pertaining to exhibitions; and scrapbooks and oversized materials. Materials in Series XVI include magnetic audio tapes and film reels of varying sizes. Materials in Series XVII include photos of works of art in her collection and exhibitions, personal photos, and snapshots taken traveling abroad. The contents of each series and subseries are described in more detail in the series-level scope and content notes.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, digital surrogates must be used when viewing the audiovisual materials in the collection.
Biography of Abby Weed Grey
Abby Weed Grey, the oldest of four children, was born on October 23, 1902, to Paul Charles Weed and Emily Weed in St. Paul, Minnesota. She grew up in St. Paul, attending both elementary and high school there. In 1920, Abby headed off east where she attended Vassar College, a private all women's college in Poughkeepsie, New York. After graduating in 1924, Abby spent the next few years (what she considered her "wander years") traveling abroad with a college roommate to Riga, Latvia, and Paris, France. Following her return from Paris in 1926, Abby started teaching fifth grade in a private school for girls in Kansas City. It was at this time that she met Lieutenant Colonel Benjamin Edwards Grey. In 1928 she became engaged and a year later married Benjamin Grey, 20 years her senior. For the next 27 years she lived as an Army wife, traveling on cross-country trips and entertaining. During that time, her husband invested in Western railroad stocks and bonds. In 1947 they purchased their first home, the family cabin in Deer Lake, Minnesota. They moved between Minnesota and Salt Lake City, Utah. In 1956 Ben died of cancer in St. Paul, Minnesota.
After Ben's death, Abby moved back to St. Paul, Minnesota. Before leaving she established the annual Benjamin Edwards Grey Memorial Lecture in poetry as part of the Summer Writers' Conference at the University of Utah.
In 1960, after being widowed for four years, Abby Grey took her first trip around the world with a group of thirteen women to Japan, Hong Kong, Thailand, Cambodia, India, Kashmir, Nepal, Pakistan, Iran, and Israel. In these foreign countries, some nearly totally unaware of Western influence, Mrs. Grey began her search for an innovative artist by meeting with working with local artists and collecting contemporary art to be shown in America.
One year later Mrs. Grey established The Ben & Abby Grey Foundation, Inc., founded for the encouragement of art through the assembling of international collections of art for cultural exchange programs. Also in 1961 she founded the "Minnesota Art Portfolio" exhibit (MAP) as an opportunity for artists to see original works by their Western counterparts. She met with Malcolm Lein, the director of the St. Paul Art Center, and selected Minnesota artists' works to bring on a trip to Spain, Greece, Italy, Turkey, and Iran. Through the United States Information Service (USIS) and the People-to-People Program, the exhibit traveled throughout the Middle East and the Mediterranean for two years. During her trip to Iran with MAP, Abby met Bishop Hassan Dehqani-Tafti of St. Luke's Church while attending Anglican services.
One artist in whom Mrs. Grey took particular interest was Iranian artist-sculptor Parviz Tanavoli, whom she met in 1961. The following year the Grey Foundation provided him a grant for six months as a visiting artist at the Minneapolis School of Art. He remained as a sculptor/instructor on staff for the following two years. In June 1964 Tanavoli returned to Iran with the gift of a bronze foundry for the University of Tehran given by the Grey Foundation.
Throughout the rest of the 1960s and early 1970s Mrs. Grey initiated many projects. These included "Fourteen Contemporary Iranians" (1962-65), which toured American cities, as did "Turkish Art Today" (1966-70), which also traveled to Tehran, Iran. Communication through Art, comprised of three exhibitions of American work, opened simultaneously in 1964 in Istanbul, Tehran, and Lahore and traveled for five years in the eastern Mediterranean, Asia, and eastern Africa. This program, which complemented the goals of USIS, was accompanied by books and catalogues representing the American art scene. Mrs. Grey also sponsored the American section of the India Triennial of Contemporary World Art in 1968. Two years later she co-sponsored it with New York's Museum of Modern Art. In 1972, "One World Through Art," an exhibition of 1,001 works from Mrs. Grey's collection, was shown at the Minnesota State Fair Grounds.
As Mrs. Grey's collection grew, she sought a place to exhibit her collection and share it with other people. At first, Mrs. Grey looked for a home for her art in her own locality. The University of Minnesota was ruled out because the gallery space available was inconvenient and the school administrators would have run the gallery. Mrs. Grey also looked at her alma mater, Vassar College, but finally chose New York University, because it gave her the flexibility that she wanted. Also, since her collection was a unique, New York City seemed the ideal place to house it. The Ben and Abby Grey Foundation, founded for the encouragement of art, donated one million dollars to NYU and in the spring of 1975, the Grey Art Gallery and Study Center was completed.
Four years later, Mrs. Grey again donated money to NYU for an art history study center that was built on the third floor of main building. In addition to the Gallery and Study Center, Mrs. Grey provided the funds to renovate the NYU undergraduate art history classrooms, auditorium and faculty offices.
By 1979, Abby Grey had become one of the foremost collectors of Asian and Middle Eastern art. She had made nine trips to Asia and had collected over 600 artworks from native artists in Egypt, Greece, Iran, India, Japan, Turkey, Pakistan, and her hometown of St. Paul, Minnesota.
On June 2, 1983, Abby Weed Grey died of cancer in St. Paul at the age of 80 years.
Throughout her life, as a patron to the arts, Mrs. Grey served on The Minnesota Society of Fine Arts (the governing body of the Minnesota Institute of Arts) Board of Trustees from 1967-73 and on the Minneapolis College of Art and Design's Board of Overseers from 1964 until her death. She established Abby Weed Grey scholarships at the College as well. At the Walker Art Center she endowed the Grey Fellowship in Museum Studies. At Hamline University she helped sponsor symposia in Near Eastern Studies and has been a benefactor to St. Catherine's College and the St. Paul Academy-Summit School. She was a member of The Women's Club of Minneapolis and The Cosmopolitan Club of New York.
Access Restrictions
The paper and photographic materials in this collection are open for use without restrictions. The collection also contains audiovisual materials that have not been digitized. Please contact the University Archives if you wish to access these materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers of Abby Weed Grey were transferred from the Grey Study Center Library of New York University to the University Archives in the Spring of 1998.
Army spouses.; Art -- Collectors and collecting.; Clippings (information artifacts); Art patrons.; Artists and patrons.; Art objects -- Collectors and collecting.; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- Exhibitions.; Islamic art |z Middle East.; Photographs.; Art, Iranian.; Scrapbooks.; Art, Turkish.; Manuscripts; Art museums -- New York (N.Y.); Notebooks; Manuscripts for publication.; Correspondence.; Diaries; Exhibition catalogs.; University of Minnesota.; University of Minnesota; Minneapolis Institute of Arts; Tanavoli, Parviz; Minneapolis Society of Fine Arts; Grey, Abby Weed, 1902-1983; Ben and Abby Grey Foundation; Grey Art Gallery & Study Center
- Series I: Book Copy, 58212
  - Subseries A: Edited, 1960-1979, 58222
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains edited drafts of Abby Weed Grey's book, published in 1983, The Picture is the Window, The Window is the Picture. They are arranged in page order and chronological order beginning with her "early years" pages 1-39. The dates included in the manuscript begin in 1902 (her birth) with earlier dates for family history. Last date on copy is 1979. Also included are notes on the organization of the book and notes on writing a book.
    - Early Years pp.1-39, undated; 58236 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      3 1142 04225385 9
    - 1st Trip Around the World, pp.40-67, 1960; 58235 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2nd Trip, Em & Hilly, pp. 68-90, 1961; 58234 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 3rd Trip "Art Form of the Ancient World", pp.91-96 & 4th Trip "Communication Through Art", pp.96-122, 1962-1964; 58233 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 5th Trip Jane Gregory, pp.124-165, 1965; 58232 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 6th Trip with Ted, pp.166-203, 1967; 58231 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 7th Trip Ellen Johnson Triennale, pp.204-230, 1968; 58230 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 8th Trip Mike, Ruth, Bettina, Turkey, pp.232-266, 1969; 58229 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - pp.267-280, undated; 58228 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Last Trip, 9th, pp.281-295, 1973; 58227 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Interim Sections, 1979; 58226 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Final Chapter: The Gift, undated; 58225 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Organization of Book, 1969; 58224 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Communication Through Art", MSS Draft, pp.1-88, 1964; 58223 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Association & Correspondence, 1975-1981, 58213
    Contains correspondence about the draft of her book. These letters include notes for the book, the outline and structure of the book, and edited pages of book.
    - "1960, 61, 62 Notes About Writing a Book (transcribed 1977), 58221 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Jeff Bedou interview with Abby Weed Grey, 1975; 58220 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Book from Sylvia Rosen, 1976; 58219 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Letty Grierson, 1978-1979; 58218 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Nancy Ann James, 1979; 58217 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Book Outline from History Ink, 1980; 58216 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence Re: Book Publication, 1981; 58215 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous MS Pages, undated; 58214 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subseries C: Additions, 1951-1993, 216156
    - Audio Tape: AWG's biography re: Art, 1981 March 17; MC151_ref2056; 216157; 1 sound cassettes (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Biography (1 of 3), Undated; 216158 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Biography (2 of 3), 1978-1993; 216159 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Biography (3 of 3), 1982-1983; 216160 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - From Abby's Day Book, 1951-1975; 216161 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases, 1983; 216162 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981; 216163 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous ("Land of the Giants"), 1979; 216164 (Box 43, Folder 7)
- Series II: Unpublished Works, 1941-1975, 58172
  Contains 7 poetry notebooks, 2 poetry small binders, 1 black binder with notes, pictures, short stories, and articles. One black binder, a scrapbook, has been separated and moved to Box 8. These notebooks and binders consist of writings about her life.
  - Early Poems (Mystical and Lyrical), undated; 58211 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1941 Outline of John Dewey; Short Stories; St. Mark's Church Work, undated; 58210 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58209 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58208 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58207 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58206 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58205 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58204 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Early Poems Notebook, undated; 58203 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notes on St. Mark's Cathedral Church, John Dewey *See Box 8, Fldr 1, undated; 58202 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Binder of Poetry, undated; 58201 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Binder of Poetry, undated; 58200 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Poetry: Exercises and Rewrites, undated; 58199 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Eye to the Sooty Crack by Abby Weed Grey, undated; 58198 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Poetry in Precise Language", 1946; 58197 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "An Eagle Came Over", 1946-1947; 58196 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Poetry is Change", 1947; 58195 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    3 1142 04225386 7
  - Corrected Notes, 1947; 58194 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Search for Other-Then-I", 1948; 58193 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Excerpts from notebooks, writings, etc., 1948-1950; 58192 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "The Pure Eye," "Who Am I," "The Electric Welcome," "Sand Paintings," What Do I Attend," "Prelude to Reality", 1949; 58191 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Need for a Feeling of Spontaneity", 1950-1951; 58190 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Poems, 1951; 58189 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "About Time and Space", 1951; 58188 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Deer Down from the Mountains", 1952; 58187 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Thoughts on Power", 1953; 58186 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Ben's Last Time at Deer Lake", 1955-1956; 58185 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Captiva" (edited by Letty), 1956; 58184 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Ben's Last Weeks on Captiva", 1958; 58183 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "The Seven Last Words of my Mother", undated; 58182 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Early Education; Years at Vassar College", undated; 58181 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Houses I Have Lived In", undated; 58180 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Memos from my letters from Vassar (1920), undated; 58179 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Resumes of letters to family from "Wander Year", undated; 58178 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Poetry-generated by "Tour of Ancient World", 1962; 58177 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "The Minnesota State Fair", 1972; 58176 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "My Wander Year (1925-26)", 1975; 58175 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "First Art Purchases", 1975; 58174 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (incorporated in other works), undated; 58173 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Series III: AWG Notebooks 1945-1978, 58142
  Contain spiral and unbound notebooks and copies of notebooks arranged chronologically by date. These consist of notes, poetry, journal entries, essays, descriptions of travel, and information regarding artists, MAP, USIA, and Parviz Tanavoli (see biographical description).
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1945; 58171 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1946-1947; 58170 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1948; 58169 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1948-1949; 58168 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1949; 58167 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook (pages; edited), 1949-1950; 58166 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1950; 58165 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1950-1951; 58164 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1952; 58163 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1953; 58162 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1953 September - 1954 September; 58161 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1954-1956; 58160 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1956 January - 1956 May; 58159 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1956-1957; 58158 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1955-1958; 58157 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Copies of Notebooks (edited), 1958-1959; 58156 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook (partially edited), 1958-1962; 58155 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1958-1963; 58154 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1964; 58153 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook (USIA, MAP, Parviz), 1961-1965; 58152 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1963 June; 58151 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    3 1142 04225387 5
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1967 August - 1968 December; 58150 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1968; 58149 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1968 December; 58148 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1970-1973; 58147 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1973 July - 1974 May; 58146 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1974 April; 58145 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1974-1976; 58144 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Abby Weed Grey Notebook, 1976; 58143 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Travel Diaries 1960-1973, 58127
  Contains diaries of travels (originals, edited, and copies), poems, and a photo essay/diary which has been separated and removed to Box 8.
  - Abby Weed Grey: Summaries of Nine Diaries, undated; 58141 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Travel Diary (1st) * See Separation Box, Fldr. 1, 1960; 58140 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Travel Diary (incomplete transcripts), 1961; 58139 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited) *See Separation Box, Fldr. 2, 1961; 58138 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Travel Diary (and Poems), Mar 1962; 58137 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Diary (rewritten in Abby's hand), 1964; 58136 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1964; 58135 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Travel Diary (mss & edited copy), 1964; 58134 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Travel Diary (original, copy & edited), 1965; 58133 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1967; 58132 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Travel Diary (taped transcript & edited), 1968; 58131 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1969; 58130 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Travel Diary (original & edited), 1973; 58129 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Photo Essay/Diary *See Photo Collection, Box 5, Fldr. 3, 1974; 58128 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Series V: Artist Files, 58033
  Contains information regarding international artists, including correspondence, published materials regarding their work, clippings, artist profiles, pamphlets. Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject/country, with most in English, although some in other languages including French and languages of the country represented. It is divided into six subseries.
  - Subseries A: General Information, 58121
    Contains general information on artists AWG associated with including a catalog, correspondence and index cards with information on specific artists mentioned in her diaries.
    - Cultural Profiles, 1961; 58126 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Grey Collection Catalogues (with additions), 1972-1973; 58125 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Artists Bios, "Deep Roots", 1964; 58124 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Artists Mentioned in Diaries (Date and Place), undated; 58123 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Artist Letters, 1974; 58122 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Greece, 58114
    Contains pamphlets, published materials, correspondence, and biographical information on specific Greek artists. Arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Guinis, Alkis *See Photo Collection, Box 4, Fldr 14, 1961-1963, 1970; 58120 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Houtopoulou-Contaratou, Sosso, 1962-1965, 1969; 58119 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Kimball, Yeffe (USA Native American), 1965; 58118 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Klonaris, Marilena, 1968; 58117 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Vakalo, G., 1961, 1963; 58116 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Spyropoulos, Jannis, 1961-1967, 1969; 58115 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Subseries C: India, 58063
    Contains pamphlets, published materials, correspondence and biographical information on specific Indian artists. Arranged alphabetically by artist.
    - Ambadas, 1968, 1970, 1973; 58113 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      3 1142 04225388 3
    - Appasamy, Jaya, 1963-1964; 58112 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Ali, J. Sultan, 1967; 58111 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Bagat, Dhan Raj, undated; 58110 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Bakre, Sadanand K., 1965; 58109 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Barwe, Prabha Kar, 1963, 1967; 58108 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bhatt, Jyoti, 1967; 58107 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Bhavsar, Natvar, 1967-1971, 1974; 58106 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Bhusan, Sudhiranjan, 1966; 58105 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Bisht, Ramesh, 1968-1969; 58104 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Chandra, Avinash, 1968; 58103 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Bisht, Ranvir S., 1969; 58102 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Dasgupta, Bimal, 1964; 58101 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Dave, Shanti, 1962-1965, 1967; 58100 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hore, Somnath, 1965; 58098 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Gaitonde, V. S., 1965; 58099 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Gujral, Satish, 1964-1967; 58097 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Gupta, Ram, 1963-1971; 58096 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Husain, 1961-1968; 58095 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Jatindas, 1968; 58094 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Kar, Sanat, 1967; 58093 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Khakkar, Bhupen, undated; 58092 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Khanna, Krishen, 1965; 58091 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Khanna, Krisha, undated; 58090 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Krishna, Devayani, undated; 58089 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Krishna, Kanwal, 1959-1964; 58088 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Lewis, Peter, undated; 58087 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Mehta, Tyeb, 1965, 1967; 58086 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Mitra, Gopal, 1967-1969, 1971; 58085 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Pai, Laxman, 1962-1966; 58084 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Padamsee, Akbar *See Photo Collection, Box 4, Fldr.15, undated; 58083 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Palsikar, S.B., undated; 58082 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Panchal, Naren, 1966-1967; 58081 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Panchal, Satish, undated; 58080 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Parikh, Jayant, undated; 58079 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Patel, Homi, 1967; 58078 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Patel, Thakor, undated; 58077 (Box 13, Folder 24)